# Pouya Mohseni

Email: mohseni0pouyai@gmail.com Mobile: +98 (933) 794-0620

#### SUMMARY

Being a Passionate student of Computer Science, I am motivated to enhance my knowledge in machine learning and data mining. Through my studies and work experiences, besides academic knowledge, I have developed many skills such as project conduction, critical thinking, and conflict resolution.

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Tehran

Tehran, Iran

Sep 2019 - Present

Bachelor of Computer Science

- o GPA: 18.16/20 (Overall: 3.85, Last two years: 4/4)
- o Thesis: Gift Recommendation Systems:
  - \* Reviewing psychological, marketing, and anthropological literature related to gift exchange in order to 1) give a clear understanding of this practice and 2) offer a framework for gift recommendation systems
  - \* Reviewing gift recommendation systems literature and examining their adherencies to the provided framework
  - $* \ \textit{Introducing a novel personality-based gift recommendation system adhered to the reviewed literature}$

Minor in Entrepreneurship

o GPA 19.29/20 (Overall: 4/4)

Salam High School

Tehran, Iran

Sep 2016 - Sep 2019

o GPA: 19.54/20 (Overall: 4/4)

High School Diploma in Mathematics and Physics

#### Research Interests

• Deep Learning

• Computer Vision

• GNNs

- Semi-Supervised Learning
- Music Generation

• Finance

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

• Programing Languages: Python, C++, Assembly, C#, R, SQL

• Frameworks & Tools: Flask, FastAPI, ASP.Net, Git, Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Keras

• Typescript Languages: Languages

## Relevant Coursework

- Deep Learning (20 out of 20)
- Artificial Intelligence (20)
- Advanced Information Retrieval (20)
- Scientific Writing (20)

- Data Structures & Algorithms (18.12)
- Design & Analysis of Algorithms (18.50)
- Linear Algebra (18.6)
- Compiler (19.16)

### EXPERIENCE

# Physics Data & Astronomical Technology (PDAT) laboratory

Tehran, Iran

Part-time Researcher

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

 Languages & Softwares: Python, LATEX, Git, Django, Docker Researching in Quantum Computing and Machine Learning Algorithms. Resulting in conducting Quantum Neural Network machine learning algorithms.

# Borhan Credit Rating

Tehran, Iran

Dec 2021 - Dec 2022

- $Part\text{-}time\ Junior\ Data\ Analyst$ 
  - $\circ\:$  Learned Software & Frameworks: Flask, Docker, Excel, Git, REST API
  - Work Results: Developed a program that rates investment funds based on the company's methodology that saves almost 5,000\$ annually. This program has a dashboard to visualize the outputs and interacts using web server protocols. Developing a Supervised Learning Model for predicting the possibility of a bank borrower's default. The model is trained on the Melal Credit Institution database.

## **Borhan Credit Rating**

Tehran, Iran

Junior Developer (Part-time) - Internship

Mar 2021 - Dec 2021

- o Learned Languages & Frameworks: C#, React, HTML, CSS, ASP.NET, Microsoft Power BI
- Work Results: Built a dashboard -visualizing the progress of different contracts- with Power BI and a webpage for itemizing fund rank results with ASP.NET & React.

### Projects

#### • Cool Compiler (Compiler Course):

Spring 2022

Developed lexical, parsing, and semantical analyzing phases of a compiler for the Cool language introduced in Standford's Compiler course. Tech: C++, Bison, FLEX

#### • Assembler & Disassembler (Machine Language and Assembly Course):

Developed Assembler & Disassembler for a restricted 8086 Assembly language supporting more than 25 instructions. Programs were developed in both Python and Assembly Languages. Tech: Python, 8086 Assembly

#### • Image processing (Data Mining Course):

Spring 2022

Developed different machine learning models for grapes' leaves classification. Many approaches are taken to achieve better accuracy, such as transfer learning, augmentation, PCA, and ensemble methods. Tech: Python, TensorFlow, Keras

# • Analysis of Packaging Industry (Business Environment in Iran Course)-A Group Project:

• Scheduling Algorithms Statistical Comparision (Fundamentals of Operating Systems Course):

Spring 2022

Prepared an analysis report for the Printing & Packaging Industry in Iran. Contains an analysis of the macro-environment of the industry and Porter's Five Forces of Competitive Position, followed by a Bussines Model for an innovative idea

Fall 2022

Conducted a statistical comparison between different Operating System Scheduling Algorithms by implanting them with Python on a suitable range of inputs. Many criteria were used during the comparison. Tech: Python

# • Natural Language Processing (Advanced Information Retrieval Course):

Fall 2022

Developed a supervised learned model for recognizing E-ezafe in Farsi sentences. Many state-of-art models were used to achieve the best results. Tech: Python

#### • Basic Computer (Principals of Computer Systems Course):

Spring 2021

Developed a basic computer whose instructions are introduced in the Digital Design book by Morris Mano. The computer was built with classical gats, and programs can be run from its RAM. Tech: Logisim

# • Predicting House Prices (Statistical Methods Course):

Spring 2021

Developed a supervised machine learning model using an ensemble of classical machine learning algorithms. Tech: R

# • Hospital Database (Database Management Systems Course):

Fall 2021

Modeled a database for a hospital with Enhanced Entity Relationship Diagram, standardized the diagrams using Normal Form methods, and implemented them via Microsoft SQL Server. Tech: SQL

#### • Leslie Matrix Research (Linear Algebra Course):

Fall 2021

Conducted research on Leslie Matrix and its usage, estimated Iran's population using population distribution, then presented in the class.

# • Messaging Program (Advanced Programming Course):

Spring 2021

Developed a messaging program containing registration, posting, replying, commenting, and liking. The program uses a terminal as the interface. Tech: C++

#### • NoteBook (Fundamentals of Computer Science and Programming Course):

Developed an advanced interactive notebook that used a terminal as the interface. The notebook has Cursor, Line Hider, and it can compile some JSON-coded instructions. Tech: Python

### Honors and Awards

• Top 0.5% at National University Entrance Exam (rank: 291)

#### LANGUAGES

• Farsi: Native Speaker

• English: Fluent